https://www.route-fifty.com/sponsors/2020/09/identity-management-how-platform-approach-can-help-safeguard-elections/168558/?oref=featured-insights

2020 Sees Largest Year-Over-Year Rise in Murder on Record
'It's All Gone Too Far:' A State Election Official Takes on Trump and the Age of Misinformation
With Vaccine Approval Imminent, States Ready Plans to Give People Their Shots
Instead of Defunding Police, Minneapolis Cuts $8 Million from Department Budget
sponsor content
RPA and Data Analytics for Comprehensive Situational Awareness
sponsor content
Contact Tracing Programs Survey Findings and Recommendations
2020 Sees Largest Year-Over-Year Rise in Murder on Record
'It's All Gone Too Far:' A State Election Official Takes on Trump and the Age of Misinformation
With Vaccine Approval Imminent, States Ready Plans to Give People Their Shots
Instead of Defunding Police, Minneapolis Cuts $8 Million from Department Budget
sponsor content
RPA and Data Analytics for Comprehensive Situational Awareness
sponsor content
Contact Tracing Programs Survey Findings and Recommendations
Self-Driving Vehicles
See all »
September 18, 2020
With the national election drawing near, state and local officials can ask themselves a these key questions to ensure they have put in place all the needed mechanisms of identity control.
Identity has long been a core concern among state and local officials charged with ensuring safe, secure and accurate voting. Are voters who they say they are? Are poll workers who access voting systems adequately and appropriately credentialed?Secretaries of state and their staffs aren’t the only ones worried about identity issues as the nation rolls toward a presidential election. An NPR/PBS NewsHour/Marist poll found that about 41 percent of Americans surveyed do not think the country is prepared to protect the election system from attack. In a 2020 survey by Okta and Juniper Research, opponents of mail-in voting cited security as their number one concern.While there are many safeguards in place to ensure voter and poll-worker identity, modernized technologies could help to further reinforce the integrity of voting systems. A platform approach to identity management could help state and local officials to better manage identity at lower cost — and with less IT intervention.Check out the resource guide from Okta to learn more!
This content is made possible by our sponsor Okta; it is not written by and does not necessarily reflect the views of RouteFifty’s editorial staff.
Share This:
Mayors Pessimistic About Cities' Prospects for Post-Covid Rebound
Electric Cargo Bikes Are Debuting in City Fleets
How to Fairly Use Algorithms to Make Tough Decisions
States Overpaid Millions in Unemployment and Now Demand People Pay It Back
Biden Will Face Limits Reversing Trump-Era Environmental Policies
Route Fifty Ebook: Cybersecurity in State & Local Government
Mayors Pessimistic About Cities' Prospects for Post-Covid Rebound
Electric Cargo Bikes Are Debuting in City Fleets
How to Fairly Use Algorithms to Make Tough Decisions
States Overpaid Millions in Unemployment and Now Demand People Pay It Back
Biden Will Face Limits Reversing Trump-Era Environmental Policies
Route Fifty Ebook: Cybersecurity in State & Local Government
×
Sign up for our daily newsletter:
×
Thank You!
Help us tailor content specifically for you:
Full Name
Agency/Department
--select--
Department of the Air Force
Department of the Army
Department of the Navy
Joint Chiefs of Staff
National Intelligence Agency
United States
EEA (European Economic Area)
Canada
Other
Country Name
Yes, Route Fifty can email me on behalf of carefully selected companies and organizations.
I agree to the use of my personal data by Government Executive Media Group and its partners to serve me targeted ads. Learn more.
Submit
Privacy Policy
Back to top
×
Route Fifty uses cookies for analytics and personalization. By continuing to use this site, you agree to our use of cookies. Read our Privacy Policy to find out more.
Thank you!
Help us tailor content specifically for you:
I Work For
Department of Defense (Civilian)
Department of Defense (Military)
EEA (European Economic Area)
Canada
Other
Yes, I want to receive occasional updates from partners
I agree to the use of my personal data by Government Executive Media Group and its partners to serve me targeted ads.
Learn more.
×
Join thousands of innovators in state and local government who start their morning with our daily newsletter.
Sign up for Route Fifty Today
Privacy Policy
Thank You!
Help us tailor content specifically for you:
Privacy Policy
